ASHISH BARAVALIYA

<u>ashishbarvaliya.job@gmail.com</u> | <u>ashishbaravaliya.com</u> Sarnia, ON

Profile

An experienced front-end developer with over **3 years** of work experience in a multinational corporation in India, currently **pursuing** post-graduation studies in full-stack software development. Additionally, working as a **senior software developer** for freelance projects on a part-time basis.

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ashishbarvaliya</u> GitHub: github.com/AshishBarvaliya

Education

Lambton College September 2022 - Present

Post-Graduation in Full Stack Software Development

3.5/4.0

Gujarat Technological UniversityAugust 2015 - May 2019

Bachelors in information technology

7.5/10

Gujarat Secondary and Higher Secondary Education Board August 2013 - April 2015

Student of Science and Math

68/100

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, C#, HTML

Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, .Net, Nodejs, GraphQL, Firebase, Netlify CMS

Tools: Azure, AWS, Git, Docker

Frontend: MUI, Tailwind CSS, Styled-component, Storybook, SAAS, Ant Design

Soft Skills: Problem solving, Quick learner, Team player, Creativity.

Work History

Freelance Remote

Senior Software Developer

August 2022 - Present

- Managing a SAAS marketplace web app single-handedly in a small startup, including overseeing all
 aspects of its development and operation
- Completed over **five projects**, including **Decentraland**, a payment invoice page, and a database management system. Each project involved utilizing a diverse range of skills, including front-end and back-end development.
- Gained proficiency in various areas including **Next.js**, **Ant Design**, **Tailwind CSS**, **Docker**, **AWS**, Stripe, **Netlify CMS**, and **team leading**.

Kerv Digital

Software Developer

Bengaluru, India December 2019 - August 2022

- In the role of a frontend developer for **2.5+ years**, responsibilities included implementing frontend designs, collaborating with teams to **deliver high-quality results**, and **presenting** work to clients.
- Developed a web portal for **LearnLight** with React, TypeScript and **Apollo GraphQL**. The portal supports LearnLight users to view profile information, keep track of learning resources and activities.
- Developed web portal with a big team for the Scouts of UK. The portal enables users to apply for permits and effectively manage profiles. utilized React, Styled Components, Redux Toolkit, and Azure to deliver a seamless user experience.

Projects

Booksaw web app [2022]

- Implemented a single-page web application for a bookstore boasts of full responsiveness.
- Skills showcase React, Typescript, MUI, enlist, husky and MUI Theming
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/bookstore

Vortex sales engine [2022]

- Developed a single page web app to showcase these skills Typescript, Rebass, CSS and Styled component.
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/vortex-sales-engine

Gesture Based Home Automation [2019]

- Created a home automation system using raspberry pi, python, and computer vision, can be used by people with disabilities (mute and deaf) to control home appliances by making a few hand gestures to the camera.
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/Hand-gesture-detection

Face detection using vgg16 [2019]

- I have developed a sophisticated face detection model using the VGG16 architecture in Python. The VGG16 architecture is a state-of-the-art deep convolutional neural network that is widely used for image recognition and classification tasks.
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/Face-detection-using-vgg16

Certifications

Python Programming Bible: Python, oops concepts, and Data structure **Project Management Simplified:** Agile, Scrum, Jira, and Grant chat.

Machine learning with python by Andrew Ng: Al and ML Algorithms

Deep learning Specialization by Andrew Ng: Neural Network, Computer Vision, and NLP